# Hector Francisco **Garcia Lara**

Full-Stack Web Software Developer

hectorglara@outlook.com http://hectorglara.ninja +1 809 819 9136 STO DGO, DR

Dear Mr. / Ms.

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a professional software developer with bachelor degree in Software Development from UTESA (Universidad Tecnologica de Santiago, DR). I have more than 8 years of experience working on different applications already crafted as well as from scratch. In my spare time, I like to play basketball and review coding in the internet to improve my development skills.

#### WHY ME?

I can assure you that I can be a really good asset for your company's development of any software you have in mind, as well as being consultant in order to boost your business. As I said I have worked from database construction to front-end view using different tools with an outstanding analysis covering all tasks necessary to build a great software. In short, I can adapt to any development environment.

"hardworking has its reward"

Sincerely

Héctor García

# Hector Francisco **Garcia Lara**

Full-Stack Web Software Developer



#### WORK EXPERIENCE

2018-PRESENT

# Senior Software Developer

At DjCity Inc.

▼ Los Angeles, United States

In charge of develoing features and optimizations to our main website (<a href="www.djcity.com">www.djcity.com</a>) as well as some internal applications that our collaborators use.

2015-PRESENT

#### Software Developer

At Banco de Reservas

■ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

My main functions are: discuss technical solutions with customers and users providing innovate new ideas, develop applications with high quality, create methodologies and resources to implement software in an easiest way.

I have led projects such as: Fiscal Invoicing, Credit Request, Employees Evaluation, Automatic Invoice Generation and Deposits Certificates.

2014-2015

#### Software Consultant

At Infosyp

■ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Contribute with the software implementation of different companies' projects, developing and testing solutions in order to get their applications optimized and easy to handle for the users and customers.

2012 - 2014

# • Flat Software Developer

At Grupo Astro SRL

■ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Create, update and maintain different softwares of our company to fulfill customers and users needs. I had the opportunity to work on two important projects: Fiscal invoicing authorization, it was a project where I had to refine all the point of sales's process in order to use a fiscal printer. Security Software, in this project I had to build a software for managing all access point of a GYM keeping in consideration everything about membership and access information.

 $\times$ 

hectorglara@outlook.com



+1 809 819 9136



https://www.linkedin.com/in/hectorglara

**⋄** SKILLS

.NET
JavaScript
SQL SERVER
AngularJS/Angular
SSIS/SSRS
Html/CSS
Photoshop
NodeJS
Web API
Oracle



### LANGUAGES

Spanish English



#### 2009 - 2012 • Junior Software Developer

At OUALA SA

■ Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

I was developing financial software for automatizing the processes, I can list: Bank Conciliation, Customer's Payments, Plane File Generation for Importing Data to others Software Platforms and Fulfillment checker (Software for auditing employees). Also I was leader in a certification process of their Financial ERP.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### 2014 - 2018 • Bachelor Degree Software Engineering

At Universidad Tecnológica de Santiago

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

Software Development and Architecture

# 2004 - 2008 • Associate / Secondary School Certificate Technical Computer

At Instituto Técnico Salesiano

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

Data Base Administration, Web/Desktop Development, Algorithms, Designs Patterns.

### 2000 - 2004 ● **Primary School**

At Oratorio Maria Auxiliadora

■ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

# Awards

# 2017 • 1<sup>st</sup> Efficient in problems resolution - CORE BANK

At BanReservas

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

#### 2010 • Individual Recognition - Administration and

At Quala SA

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

#### 2011 • Best Team

At Quala SA

▼ Sto Dgo, Dominican Republic

hectorglara@outlook.com

+1 809 819 9136

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hectorglara